(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-22T21:04:07.012688",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
いくよ
Here we go!
はちゃめちゃカラフルデイズ
A chaotic, colorful days,
攻略法を探している
Searching for a walkthrough.
リセットボタンなんてあるわけないし
There's no reset button anyway,
縛りプレイもいい所じゃない
And it's quite a challenge run, too.
そんなのわかりきってる
We already know that.
それなら思い出して
If so, remember
夢を奏でるあの星のことを
That star playing our dreams.
最初はダメダメでもいいからさ
It's fine if we're useless at first,
ほらリズムに合わせて one, two, try and try
Come on, match the rhythm, one, two, try and try.
予測不可能なんだ本当のところは
The truth is, it's completely unpredictable,
次のページのことだろ？ (I don't know)
It's about the next page, right? (I don't know)
怖いことなんてないよ
There's nothing to be afraid of.
その続きにいせーので飛び込んじゃおう
Let's dive right into what comes next on three!
だから do my best, do my best テンションは弾けて
So do my best, do my best, excitement popping!
ドキドキのボリュームは max でいこうよ attention, please
Let's max out our pounding volume, attention please!
泣いちゃって笑っちゃってエモーションもアタフタしてる
Crying, laughing, our emotions are all flustered.
この今をめいっぱいさあ楽しんでいこうよ
Let's enjoy this present moment to the fullest!
まだまだ、まだなの止まれないそんな世界が大好きなんだよ
Still not stopping, I just love a world like this!
声に出して do my best
Say it out loud, do my best!
ちんぷんかんぷんカラフルデイズ
Gibberish, colorful days,
冒険の書はどこにもない
There's no adventure book anywhere.
セーブポイントやり直しの毎日じゃ
With save points and daily retries,
ワクワクの音色も奏でられない
We can't even play exciting melodies.
そんなのつまらないでしょ？
Isn't that boring?
それなら耳を澄ませて
If so, listen closely,
大好きな音が聴こえてくるよ
Your favorite sounds are coming through.
明日は明日の風が吹くからさ
Tomorrow is another day, so
ほらリズムに合わせて one, two, try and try
Come on, match the rhythm, one, two, try and try.
やっぱり気になってしまうな本当のところは
The truth is, we still can't help wondering,
次のページのことだろ (I want to know)
It's about the next page (I want to know).
溢れるリズム繋いで
Connecting overflowing rhythms,
君だけの気持ちを今すぐ描いちゃおう
Let's sketch out your feelings right now!
だから do my best, do my best
So do my best, do my best,
クエスチョンがぐるぐる回り白昼夢中
Questions spinning in a daytime dream.
attention, please, attention, please
キラキラのドリームは max でいこうよ
Let's max out our sparkling dreams!
単純で難解なエモーションにアタフタしてる
Flustered by simple yet baffling emotions.
これからもめいっぱいさあ仲良くよろしくね
Let's keep getting along great from now on!
まだまだ、まだあとどれくらい？
Still, how much longer until then?
そんな明日を目指して行こうもう一歩 do my best
Aiming for that tomorrow, take another step, do my best!
お星様にお願い事
A wish upon a star,
はやくそれになれますように
Hoping it comes true soon!
覚えないように魔法をかけて
Cast a spell so we won't forget.
ワクワクが爆発しちゃいそう
Excitement is about to explode!
今気付いちゃったんだ本当のところは
I just realized the truth is
次のページのことだろ？ (I don't wait)
It's about the next page? (I don't wait)
楽しみすぎるからさ
Because we're just too excited,
その続きにいせーので飛び込んじゃおう
Let's dive right into what comes next on three!
だから do my best, do my best
So do my best, do my best,
テンションは弾けてくらりこみゅにてぃー
Excitement popping, dizzy community.
attention, please, attention, please
ドキドキのボリュームは max でいこうよ
Let's max out our pounding volume!
泣いちゃって笑っちゃってエモーションもアタフタしてる
Crying, laughing, emotions all flustered.
この今をめいっぱいさあ楽しんでいこうよ
Let's enjoy this present moment to the fullest!
まだまだ、まだなの止まれないそんな世界に大好き宣言
Still not stopping, I declare my love for this world!
声に出して do my best
Say it out loud, do my best!
合言葉は do my best
Our secret password is do my best!
どぅーまいべすと！
Do my best!
いつだって フルフル全力
Always giving it my all, full throttle!
はじけちゃって テンション プリティ
Bursting with cute energy,
キラキラノートに ボンマックスしようよ
Let's fill up our sparkling notebooks!
感じてナンカイナイ エモーションにアタフタして
Feeling unknown emotions and getting flustered,
これからもめいっぱい仲良くよろしくね！
Let's keep being great friends from now on!
もう一歩 もう一歩 つぎのまいべすと！
One more step, another step to my best!
お星さまに お願いごと
Making a wish upon the stars,
はやくそれになれますように ため息ないように
Hoping to reach it soon without any sighs,
魔法をかけて わくわく ワクワク ふしぎデコレーション
Casting a magic spell, exciting and wonderful!
ドキドキ わくわく ワクワク 不思議だいこうにん
Thumping with excitement, officially amazing!
みんなでソラをあおげ！
Look up at the sky together!
今気付いちゃったんだ
I just realized it now,
本当のところは 次のページの事だよ
The real truth is on the next page!
アイ・ドント・ノウ・ウェイ！
I don't know way!
楽しみすぎるから さくっと進む期に
I'm way too excited, so let's quickly move on,
異世界のね とびこんじゃおう！
Let's leap into another world!
どぅーまいべすと！ どぅーまいべすと！
Do my best! Do my best!
テンションは弾けて ぐらりこちむいて
Tension bursting, tilting this way and that,
アテンションプリー… ドキドキのボリュームマックス
Attention please... Volume max for our hearts!
大ちゃくしてわらっちゃって エモーションもあたふたして
Laughing it off, emotions all flustered,
この今をめいっぱいさ 楽しんでいこうよ！
Let's enjoy this present moment to the fullest!
まだまだまだまだ あどれくらい そんなあしたを
Still, how much longer should we aim for such a tomorrow?
世界中大すき！ 全力で声に出して
Loving the whole world! Shouting it out with all my might,
どぅーまいべすと！ 愛のことばは
Do my best! The words of love are...
どぅーまいべすと！ おおぞらスバル！ ホントにマジにリアルにライブ！ はじまるよー！
Do my best! Oozora Subaru! Truly, seriously real live! It's starting!
君は聴こえる？
Can you hear it?
僕のこの声が
This voice of mine?
闇に虚しく 吸い込まれた
Sucked away into the empty darkness...
もしも世界が 意味を持つのなら
If this world has any meaning after all,
こんな気持ちも 無駄ではない？
Then aren't these feelings worth having?
憧れに押しつぶされて あきらめてたんだ
Crushed by longing, I had almost given up.
果てしない空の色も 知らないで
Without even knowing the color of the endless sky,
走り出した想いが今でも
The feelings I started running with, even now,
この胸を確かに叩いているから
Are beating strongly and steadily inside my chest.
今日の僕が その先に続く
Today's me will continue beyond that,
僕らなりの明日を 築いていく
Building our very own tomorrow.
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer, yes, is always right here.
過ぎた季節を 嘆く暇はない
There's no time to lament passing seasons,
二度と迷って しまわぬように
So I won't lose my way ever again.
数えきれない ほのささやかな
Countless subtle and quiet
そんな後悔抱えたまま その背中だけ追いかけてここまで来たんだ
Regrets held close, I chased your back to get this far.
探していた 僕だけにできること
I was searching for what only I could do.
あの日くれた言葉が今でも
The words you gave me that day, even now,
この胸に確かに届いているから
Are still reaching deep within my heart.
昨日よりも 今日 僕は僕の
More than yesterday, today I'm discovering
生まれてきた理由に気付いていく
The reason I was born into this world.
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer, yes, is always right here.
君は聴こえる? 僕のこの声が
Do you hear it? My voice
闇に虚しく 吸い込まれた
Engulfed by the darkness in vain
もしも世界が 意味を持つなら
If the world has any meaning
こんな気持ちも 無駄ではない?
Are these feelings not in vain either?
憧れに押しつぶされて あきらめてたんだ
Crushed by longing, I had given up
果てしない空の色も 知らないで
Without even knowing the color of the endless sky
走り出した想いが今でも
The feelings that started running
この胸を確かに叩いているから
Are still definitely pounding against my heart
今日の僕がその先に続く
So today's me will continue beyond that
僕らなりの明日を築いていく
And build our own kind of tomorrow
答えはそう いつもあるここにある
The answer is always right here
グラスの氷 カラカラかき回して
Stirring the ice in my glass, clinking around
ほらなんかいい 感じでしょね
Doesn't that feel just right?
ちょっと足も組んでみて
Cross your legs a little bit
そっと遠くを見つめ なんかそれっぽいfeeling
And gently gaze into the distance, with that kind of feeling
大人ぶったsummer time
Acting all grown-up this summer time
だけど私には全然物足りない
But it's still not nearly enough for me
裸足になって海へ行きたい
I want to go barefoot to the ocean
すぐに!
Right now!
水着に着替え go dive
Change into a swimsuit, go dive
高鳴る水しぶき じゃ足りないわ
Splashing water isn't enough
濡れた髪 結んで 大胆なlady
Tie up my wet hair, like a daring lady
ギラギラ焼けたsunshine小麦肌
Dazzling burnt sunshine on tanned skin
私らしく夏をメイクしちゃうからね!
Because I'll make up my summer just like me until morning!
熱くなりすぎた身体
My body grew a bit too warm
クリームソーダでcool down
Cool down with a cream soda
こだわりブレンド サングラスかけ
With a special blend and sunglasses on
パラソルの下で優雅なスタイル
An elegant style under the parasol
決まってるね
Looking so good
砂浜を舞うビーチボール急に頭をよぎる君の姿
A beach ball dancing on the sand, your figure suddenly crosses my mind
来年こそは二人きりで過ごせたら
If only we could spend next year just the two of us
照り出す身体
My glowing body
潮風浴びて
Bathed in the sea breeze
イヤフォン越しのサマートゥーン
A summer tune through my earphones
上がる
Rising
体温 今気分は最高潮だから もうダメ!
My body temperature and mood are at their peak, so no more!
水着に着替え go dive
Change into a swimsuit, go dive
高鳴る全身で海感じたいわ
Want to feel the ocean with my whole body
姫を占わないではじけちゃって
Don't hold back, just burst out and go wild
キラキラ高まり到来
Sparkling excitement arrives
これぞ夏の真髄 大人にあこがれた日々
This is the true essence of summer, days I longed to be grown up
もう少し子供のままで 私らしく夏をメイクしちゃおう!
Staying just a little bit like a child, let's make up our summer just like us!
曖昧3センチ そりゃぴにってコトかい?
Three centimeters, it's a rule we can overlook?
じょっ らぴんぐが制服
My sailor uniform is lucky,
とか不利ってことない
so I'm off the hook!
ぷっ がんばっちゃ？ やっちゃっちゃ
Hypocrite, just do it!
そんときゃちゃっかり&Release
Pull back and release it, yeah!
あせっふっ あせっふっ
No sweat! No sweat!
ほっそりまりだりなりFree!!
You got it going, darlin' darlin' freeze!
なんかダルー なんかデルー
Feeling kinda lazy, borderlin' in' crazy
あいしてルー あれ一個が違ってるんルー
Wait, no, I think maybe I love you!
やみんぼうぽー 鉄骨ぼー おしんぼうぽー
Worry wort, no, wait, introvert, miss food court
いい加減にしなさいっ!
Hey, just cut it out!
踏んづけたアイツのホテルからだって いわゆる普通のオンナのコ動いた
I don't get what's cool 'bout the new girl, but she's loved like the last in the whole world
あたしだけトコトコ針金お下がりカタカタタ
Is it just me? She's just a schoolgirl!
ボンボンおーえん団 Let's get!
Pom-pom cheerleader, let's get!
チェリーパイ ランランかんげー会
Cherry pie, la, la, welcome home
Look up! せんせーしょん はい!
Look up! Party sensation (yeah!)
存在感..小惑星 ぶつかって溶けましたぼーぜん
Brilliant confidence, shooting star!
大いに歌ってシレンジャー
Take it away, squad ranger
もっていけ! 最後に笑っちゃうのはあたしのはず
I'll be the one that will have the last laugh
セーラーふくだからです→結論
And I'll rock my sailor uniform like no big deal
月曜日なのに! 機嫌悪いのどうするよ?
I'm at a loss, I don't know what to do
夏服がいいのです→キャ? ワ! イイv
It's Monday, so I'm in a bad mood
接近3ピクセル するまでってゅーちょだ
But at least my sailor uniform is super cute!
もっていけ! 最後に笑っちゃうのはあたしのはず セーラーふくだからです→結論
I'll be the one that will have the last laugh in my sailor uniform!
月曜日なのに! 機嫌悪いのどうするよ? 夏服がいいのです→キャ? ワ! イイv
It's Monday, but at least my sailor uniform is super cute!
ぐっ がんばって! やっちゃっちゃ!
You'll kill it! (yay!)
そんときゃちゃっかり&Please
My darlin' darlin', please
もりあがりー もりさがりー 恋したりー まだ内緒にしときてりー
Love makin' me blur like a roller coaster, wait, no, can we keep that a secret?
甘えぼー用心棒通しんぼー
Look at you fight back like that spoiled brat
ちょーしこいてギョクサキ
Red flag, you better cut it out!
あなたの背中からだって いわゆる普通のオンナのコ動いた
Look at you fight back like that spoiled brat
私だけトコトコ針金お下がりカタカタタ
Now I'm in control, and, hey I'm on a roll
もんもんはぼりさがりこりさがり
Mon-mon delusion, let's go back in time
まだいそにしといてりんり
Yai, yai soarin' moves, what's up temptation?
甘えんぼうじんぼうつうしんぼう
Need a part-time job, 'cause I'm broke as heck
ちょーしこいてよくさい
I'm gonna be set for life, so just sit back
踏んづけたアイツにこゆびいたいって
And watch as I sing and dance
おおげさちらりくろにはい
Give it a try and give it all you got
せっかいじゃんりょいきじゃん生足づるぴかおねだりだだだ
The challenge you now face needs your best shot
もんもんもーそー伝 Let's go!
Underneath my sailor uniform, I am still me
パル神殿 YAI-YA! そーらん節 What's up?
The weekend's here but what's there to do
てんぺってーしょん おおい!
But show off whenever I'm near you?
喪失感‰アルバイト さがしたら見つかってとーぜん 人生まるっとケネンカネシ
With this simple sailor uniform, life sure is great!
新規に狙っちゃうのはあたしの挑戦 セーラーふく着替えてもあたし
Make my heart race when we embrace
週末はどうよ? 制服はかんたんよ=ラクチン
I'm sugar, sugar sweet!
風速3メートル 抱きつかれがまんまぎゅ
Bon - bon, mon-mon day
胸ドッキン 腰ゾッキン I'm sugar sugar SWEET!!
Let's get ooh, ooh, ah
ボン・ボン・オーエン団 Let's get!
Ran - ran chop, chop, kick!
ウッ・ウッ・アーッ! ラン・ラン・チョップ・チョップ・キック!
Look up! Fu, fu, ho! (yeah!)
Look up! フッ・フッ・ホッ! はい! エデュケーション!!
Learning's so easy! Love is a - b - c
LOVE IS ABC ウンダカダァ ウンダカダァ
I fall in love, I fall in love
ウニャウニャ ハレッチ ホレッチ ヒネンラー
Ooh, la, la everyone now, sing and dance
もっていけ! 最後に笑っちゃうのはあたしのはず セーラーふくだからです→結論
Take it all and be on the attack
月曜日なのに! 機嫌悪いのどうするよ?
I'll be the one that will have the last laugh
夏服がいいのです→キャ? ワ! イイv
And I'll rock my sailor uniform like no big deal
やっぱりね 最後に笑っちゃうのはあたしのはず
I'm at a loss, I don't know what to do
セーラーふくだからです→結論
It's Monday, so I'm in a bad mood
曖昧3センチ そりゃぴにってコトかい? わお! らっぴんぐが制服...よろし不易ってことない
Three centimeters, it's a rule we can overlook
ぷっ がんばっちゃ? やっちゃっちゃ
Hypocrite, just do it!
そんときゃちゃっかり&Release
Pull back and release it, yeah!
あせっふっ あせっふっ
No sweat! No sweat!
ほっそりまりだりなりFree!!
You got it going, darlin' darlin' free!
ボン・ボン・オーエン団 Let's get!
Bon - bon, mon-mon day
ウッ・ウッ・アーッ! ラン・ラン・チョップ・チョップ・キック!
Let's get ooh, ooh, ah
Look up! フッ・フッ・ホッ! はい! エデュケーション!!
Ran - ran chop, chop, kick!
LOVE IS ABC ウンダカダァ ウンダカダァ
Look up! Fu, fu, ho! (yeah!)
ウニャウニャ ハレッチ ホレッチ ヒネンラー
Learning's so easy! Love is a - b - c
もっていけ! 最後に笑っちゃうのはあたしのはず セーラーふくだからです→結論
I fall in love, I fall in love
月曜日なのに! 機嫌悪いのどうするよ?
Ooh, la, la everyone now, sing and dance
夏服がいいのです→キャ? ワ! イイv
Take it all and be on the attack
やっぱりね 最後に笑っちゃうのはあたしのはず セーラーふくだからです→結論
I'll be the one that will have the last laugh
曖昧3センチ そりゃぴにってコトかい?
And I'll rock my sailor uniform like no big deal
わお! らっぴんぐが制服...
I'm at a loss, I don't know what to do
つかれたー！
I'm exhausted!
つかれたー！やばい！
I'm exhausted! So crazy!
みんな息切れやばない？息切れやばい！
Everyone, are you guys out of breath? We're so out of breath!
やばすぎない？やばすぎない？
Isn't it crazy? Isn't it crazy?
考えられない、やばい。
I can't even believe it, it's crazy.
お前元気だな、ちょこせんせい。
You've got so much energy, Choco-sensei.
めちゃめちゃキックアップしてた、今の中継で。
You were kicking it up so much during that broadcast just now.
お前、もう、二人見てたらさ、
You guys were looking at us like, man,
見てたらさ、すごいなと思って。
seeing you two, we thought it was amazing.
よかったね、よかったね。
It was great, wasn't it? It was great.
そういうことですね、そういうことですね。
That's right, that's right.
やっぱもっていけ！セーラーふくでした！パチパチパチ！
After all, it was "Motteke! Sailor Fuku"! Clap clap clap!
はいどうもこんにちは！みなさんどうですかこのポンポン
Hello there! Everyone, what do you think of these pom-poms?
かわいいでしょー！
Aren't they cute?
これですね、ちょっとポンポンを作ってみました！
We actually made these pom-poms ourselves!
女子会なんですね！写真って撮りますか？
Since it's a girls' night! Do you take pictures?
おー！いいですね！撮りたい！撮りたい！
Oh! That's nice! I want to take some!
集合集合！結構ね、大きいからね。
Gather around! They're pretty big, you know.
いやちょっと身長高いから、ちょっと後ろ行って、真ん中行きなさい早く。
Wait, you're tall, go to the back, get in the middle, hurry up!
なんなんだお前は！何持ってんだお前！
What is your deal?! What are you holding?!
いやちょっとしゃがむか。
Well, maybe I'll squat down.
そこでね、膝ついて
Kneel down right there,
こうする？こうする？
and do this? Do this?
はい！もうちょい持ったんじゃ、左側がいいかな。
Yes! Hold it a bit more, left side might be good.
こっち？あ、いいですね。
Here? Oh, that's good.
ちょこせんもう1歩、内側がいいかな。
Choco-sen, one more step inward might be good.
こんぐら？
About this?
あ、いいですね！
Ah, that's nice!
いいですねー！えーー！
Very nice! Eeeee!
シャンシャンシャン、顔隠れる、顔隠れる。
Click click click, your face is hidden, face is hidden.
はい！シャンシャンシャンシャン、チェキ撮影してください！
Yes! Click click click, please take cheki photos!
お願いしまーす！一番のお願いしまーす！
Please! That's my #1 request!
はい、ということでですね、せっかくなんでね、
Right, so since we have the chance,
1人ずつも撮ってみるか！
let's take individual photos too!
お！いいねいいね！
Oh! Nice, nice!
最初だれから？ボタンちゃん？
Who's first? Botan-chan?
あ、し！
Ah, shi—
あ、お！
Ah, o!
じゃあちょっとみんな飛び蹴りスクショを頼む！
Alright everyone, I request a flying kick screenshot!
いいね！
Nice!
めちゃめちゃ映り込んどるやないか！
You're totally in the shot!
お前元気だなマジで
Man, you've got so much energy.
はい、胸の前で持つのがかわいいよ。
Yes, holding it in front of your chest is cute.
あ、こう、こう、こう、こう。
Ah, like this, like this, like this.
かわいい！シャンシャンシャン、なんでその顔なんだよ！
Cute! Click click click, why are you making that face?!
いいですね！そして、ルナ！
Very nice! And next, Luna!
はい！
Yes!
なんやねん！なんか出てきた！
What the heck! Something popped out!
なんか出てきた！なんだこれ？
Something came out! What is this?
かわいい！
Cute!
あ、かわいい！
Ah, cute!
いいよいいよ、早く座れ行きなさい！
Good, good, hurry up and sit down, go!
お前めっちゃ元気だな！
You've got so much energy!
はい、ということでですね、
Right, so,
本日の主役！こんにちは！
today's main character! Hello!
大空スバルでーす！
I'm Oozora Subaru!
似合うね、黄色似合うね。
It suits you, yellow suits you.
めちゃめちゃ似合ってる！似合ってるわ！
It suits you so much! It really does!
はい、ということでね、ありがとうございます！
Alright, so thank you very much!
かわいい！
Cute!
いいねーらね！
See ya later!
じゃあちょこせん！
Next is Choco-sen!
似合うねー！いいね、かわいい！
It suits you! Nice, cute!
ちょっとセクシーだな。
It's a bit sexy.
やっぱセクシーだな。なんか手が目立ってねーか？
Yeah, really sexy. Wait, aren't your hands standing out?
確かに！挟んでんじゃねーよポンポンを！
True! Don't sandwich the pom-poms like that!
しょうがないじゃん！
It can't be helped!
しょうがないじゃない、目立たなくていーよ！
It can't be helped, it's fine if they don't stand out!
はい、ということで、じゃあ集合！
Alright, so, everyone gather!
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho.
ちょこせんもね、ポンポンおいしいくてね。
Choco-sen's pom-poms look delicious too.
はい、ということでですね、ここまでね、ライブをやってきて初MCなんですけれども！
Right, so up to this point, we've done some live songs and this is our first MC!
どうだったスバルのライブはさ！
How was Subaru's live performance?!
めちゃめちゃかわいかった！
It was super cute!
でもバトンすごくなかった？
But wasn't the baton amazing?
バトンびっくりした！
The baton was surprising!
ちょっとね、まあ練習しました！
We, well, practiced it!
ごはんのために行ったときさ、遅れてきてさ、ごはん遅れたって
When I went for dinner, I was late, and when I said dinner was late,
バトンめっちゃ持ってたの！
you were holding the baton so much!
もう本当にね、天分、天賦の、みんなお待たせ！
Truly, it's a natural gift... Everyone made you wait!
ごはん早いってさ、なんでポン持ってんの？とか言ってたら今日のオープニングだったんだよね。
When I said dinner is early, why are you holding pom-poms? And then it turned out to be today's opening.
結構ね、前前からね、練習してたりとかしてました！
Quite a bit, we'd been practicing since way before!
はい、そしてですね、ちょこね、このあとね、新情報があるんですよ！
Right, and then, Choco, after this, there's new information!
なんだって！？
What?!
段取りのようなセリフ
That sounds like scripted dialogue!
助かる、なんか段取りのようなことを聞くけど。
Helpful, though it sounds like rehearsed stuff.
1種類かい！
Just one kind?!
やっちゃったね、それね！
You messed that up, didn't you!
もう、なんて言ったらいいのこれ！
Geez, what am I supposed to say to this!
一種類！そうになのら？
One kind! Is that so, nanora?
本当に？
Really?
ちょっと！
Hold on!
ちょっと上に行っちゃった、これちょっと見ないと。
It went a bit high up, we gotta look at this.
でもね、もう腰抜かしちゃったよスバルは。
But you know, Subaru's knees gave out.
自分て！
Yourself?!
自分てね！
Yourself, yeah!
まあまあ、今年4周年ですからね、スバル！
Well, it's 4 years this year, Subaru!
そうですね！
That's right!
4周年になりました！ありがとうございます！
It's been 4 years! Thank you very much!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ルナ、マジで体調ついたね。
Luna, you really got the hang of it.
え、ほんと？
Eh, really?
全然息切れしてないじゃん、本当だよ。
You're not out of breath at all, seriously.
息切れ、息切れ！
Out of breath, out of breath!
めちゃめちゃ元気！
Super energetic!
すごいよ、アイドルってこんなにすごいんだ！
Amazing, idols are this incredible!
すげえ！すごいだな！
Awesome! That's amazing!
はい、ということでですね、このあともまだまだ続くのでね、よかったらみなさんぜひ応援してください！
Right, so, since it's going to continue even more after this, please everyone continue cheering for us!
はい、それでは！
Alright, then!
次も頑張るから、みんな本当にありがとね！
We'll do our best next time too, thank you so much everyone!
頑張ったね！
You did your best!
ありがとう！またね！
Thank you! See you later!
またね！
See you!
はい！
Yes!
ということですね、それではですね、やばい、1人になっちゃった！
Right, so, well then, oh no, I'm all by myself!
ここからもですね、まだまだみんなが大驚きするようなことがいっぱいあると思うので、楽しみにしていてください！
From here on too, there's still a lot of things that will surprise everyone, so please look forward to it!
はい、それではですね、次の曲に行きたいと思います！
Alright, then, I'd like to move on to the next song!
何が始まるかは曲が始まってからのお楽しみです！
What will start is a surprise until the song begins!
それではですね、行きますよ！
Alright then, here we go!
同じ未来を見たい
I want to see the same future,
あの夢手に入れたい
I want to make that dream mine.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れgo!
Running with our different hearts, go!
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われて
Our eyes were captured by a tiny hope.
不安で揺れる心をうまくチューニングして
Tuning our swaying hearts of anxiety well,
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
we mustered up a tiny bit of courage.
キラキラの太陽が ワクワクが待ちきれない！
The glittering sun, we can't wait for the excitement!
あれもしたいこれもしたいねSummer Time!
We want to do that, we want to do this, Summer Time!
青い空と白い雲が心のボルテージ上げて行く
The blue sky and white clouds raise the voltage in our hearts.
ラムネ色のTシャツはね 今年いちばんのレコメンド
A ramune-colored T-shirt is this year's top recommendation.
走り出した海岸線 どこまでだって行けそうだね
Running along the coastline, it feels like we can go anywhere.
数え切れない夏休みだね 君も一緒に行こう
It's an endless summer vacation, let's go together too!
あっという間に進んでく時計
The clock ticks away in the blink of an eye,
短すぎじゃない？マイ・サマー・タイム
isn't it too short, my summertime?
ぜんぶ最後の思い出にするんだ 追い風
Let's make it all our final memories, tailwind,
みんな連れてって！素晴らしい太陽がサンサンと照って ジャンプ！
take everyone along! The wonderful sun shines down brilliantly, jump!
弾ける汗！宝石みたいにキラキラ眩しく輝け
Splashing sweat! Sparkling and shining like jewels,
キラキラの太陽が ドキドキがいっぱいです！
the glittering sun is full of heart-pounding excitement!
あれもしようこれもやろう Let's Summer Time!
Let's do that, let's do this, Let's Summer Time!
ちょこっとヤンチャで にこっと謙虚な
A bit mischievous, yet smilingly modest,
キラっとスマイル 愛取（アイ・トール）る
a flashing smile, capturing your love.
毎日もっと楽しくしたい貪欲ウィズ・アドベンチャー
An ambitious with-adventure wanting to make every day more fun.
しらばっかしたって もうちゃんと聞きこなせるんだよ
Even if you play dumb, I can hear it right through.
宝物をもっと気になってもいいよ一緒に
You can be curious about treasures even more, together!
お空に飛び立った後も 光れスターライト
Even after taking off into the sky, shine, starlight!
真ん中 輝きの中も 強いきらめき
Right in the center, amidst the brilliance, a strong twinkle,
キミに届いているかな １ミリでも伝われバイオ・チャージ！
I wonder if it reaches you. Even by a millimeter, get across, bio-charge!
チャレンジ全力あふせる 頑張るキミへ
To you who give your all in challenges and overflow with effort,
一番のりのスマイルを贈る スバル・チャンネル
sending the number-one smile, Subaru Ch.
憧れの舞台立ちたい 楽しく輝きたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams, I want to shine happily.
時に涙して また笑い合いたい
Sometimes shedding tears, and wanting to laugh together again.
同じ未来を見たい あの夢手に入れたい
I want to see the same future, I want to make that dream mine.
踏み出そう 奇跡の 一歩を
Let's take that miraculous step forward!
生き生きとして夢を追いかけたい
Vibrantly chasing our dreams,
ワクワクで止まらない 想像を越えてく
unstoppable with excitement, surpassing imaginations,
世界に見せてあげる アクセスしてみたいな 後悔なんてここにない
we'll show it to the world. I want to access it, there are no regrets here.
それぞれ違ったココロでつくるんだよ
Creating it with our respective hearts,
それぞれ違ったココロで つくるworld
creating a world with our respective hearts.
息切らし して夢追いかけたい ワクワク止まらない 想像越えてく世界見せてあげる
Breathing hard, wanting to chase dreams, unstoppable with excitement, showing you a world beyond imagination.
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me more! Look at me more!
恩返しは“愛のこもった投げキスで”
My repayment is "with a kiss thrown full of love".
気のせいじゃない 目合ってるよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting.
ハート作って 恋しちゃって 下さい！
Make a heart, fall in love, please!
気のせいじゃない 目は合ってるよ
It's just my imagination, our eyes are meeting.
ハート作って 恋しちゃって下さい！
Make a heart and fall in love!
やれること 何でもします
I'll do anything you ask of me.
NG無しで体当たり挑戦
A head-on challenge with zero restrictions!
エゴサで見つけたアンチのコメ
Anti comments I found while ego-searching...
ふざけんな…誰より分かってるし
Give me a break! I understand that better than anyone.
でも大丈夫 ここに立てばみんながいる
But it's okay, everyone's here if I stand on this stage.
行くよ！
Come on!
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love! More! Look at me! More!
恩返しは
My token of gratitude is...
“愛のこもった投げキスで” 虜にする！
"With a love-filled flying kiss," I'll capture your heart!
もっと！夢を見せる！もっと！
More! Show me dreams! More!
楽しんでって 愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Enjoy yourselves in this love-filled special night!
ファンサしちゃうぞ(・ω<)
I'm gonna give you some fan service! (*>ω<*)
お便りも書いてください！
Please write me letters too!
何度も読んで 宝物にします
I'll read them over and over and treasure them.
スキャンダル まだ早いけど
A scandal is still too early,
裏切りません！宣言しときます(｀・ω・´)
but I won't betray you! I declare it now (`・ω・´).
嫉妬、嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to jealousy or teasing.
ふざけんな！実力で勝ってやる
Give me a break! I'll win with pure skill!
だから辞めない 負けず嫌い 私はいる
That's why I won't quit, sore loser that I am, I am here!
行くよ！
Here we go!
こぶし上げて！もっと！汗をかいて！もっと！
Raise your fists! More! Work up a sweat! More!
恩返しは
My token of gratitude is...
“愛のこもったスバビームで” 大歓声！
"With a love-filled Suba-beam," to great cheers!
もっと！まだまだ！ねぇ？もっと！
More! Still not enough, hey? More!
受け止めてね 愛のこもったわがままソング
Please accept this love-filled selfish song!
ファンサしちゃうぞ(・ω<)
I'm gonna give you some fan service! (*>ω<*)
はぁ…終わりが近づく 寂しいね
Ah... the end is approaching, how lonely.
楽しいのに 泣きそうだよ
Even though it's fun, I feel like crying.
次も 次も また会えるよね？
We can meet again next time, right?
今日はみんなのおかげで 最後の4周年になりました！
Today is everyone's day, we've reached our 4th anniversary!
本当に今日はありがとうございます！
Thank you so much today!
優しさに溢れている言葉も 心ない誰かの言葉さえも
Even words overflowing with kindness, or someone's thoughtless words...
必要なんだ
They're necessary!
必要なんだ 強くなろうよ
They're necessary, let's become strong!
好きに叫べ！もっと！楽しんじゃえ！もっと！
Shout it out! More! Let's enjoy it! More!
忘れないで 特別な日になりますように
Don't forget it, so it becomes a special day!
共に歌おうずっと！共に歩もうずっと！
Let's sing together forever! Let's walk together forever!
合言葉はとびっきりのＬ・Ｏ・Ｖ・Ｅ！
Our secret word is a heartfelt L-O-V-E!
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love! More! Look at me! More!
恩返しは
My token of gratitude is...
“愛のこもった投げキスで” 虜にする！
"With a love-filled flying kiss," I'll capture your heart!
もっと！夢を見せる！もっと！
More! Show me dreams! More!
楽しんでって 愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Enjoy yourselves in this love-filled special night!
ファンサしちゃうぞ(・ω<)
I'm gonna give you some fan service! (*>ω<*)
はい、ということでファンサでした！
Alright, so that was fan service!
みんな、どうですかこの可愛い新衣装！
Everyone, how is this cute new outfit?
可愛いでしょう？
It's cute, right?
ちょっとスバルもね、全力で全力で踊っちゃったからさ(笑)
Subaru danced with all her energy and strength, so she's out of breath!
この最高な新衣装は、スバルの母ちゃん、シグレウイ母ちゃんに作ってもらいました！イェーイ！
This top-tier new outfit was made by Chigusa Gacha-chan! Yay!
この可愛いリボン！
Look at this cute ribbon!
そして、その二…みんなね、何か見たことがあるなと思った人もいるんじゃないでしょうか！
And then, don't you think some of you have seen something like this before?
そうなんです！この衣装ですね、新衣装の、スバルの新衣装…あのアイドル衣装のね、新バージョンとなっております！
That's right, this outfit is a new version of Subaru's idol outfit!
ということでね、このズボンなんかもね…なんか、見たことあるな、という
Even these shorts... you've probably seen them before!
ちょっとお納めがね ポンポンが回る…そうというね可愛らしい衣装になっております。
My tummy is round... yes, it's become a really cute outfit like that.
あとここね コサージュとかもね
And here too, the corsage and everything...
可愛いでしょう！
Isn't it cute!
帽子もね まんまるでおしゃれなんだよね。
The hat is also round and cute, you know.
めちゃまんまる！ね、ひまわりもつけてもらいました！
Super round! See, they even put a sunflower on it!
手袋も わあー！
The gloves too, wow!
はい、ということでぜひね、たくさんスクショをして、スクショをして、スクショをして！
So yeah, please take lots of screenshots, screenshots, screenshots!
え、ぜひね、Twitterでつぶやいてください！みんなのおかげです、ありがとーー！
Please tweet it out on Twitter! It's thanks to everyone, thank you so much!
はい、ということでですね、このあとも…なんと、この衣装はまだこれだけじゃない！
So yeah, after this... amazingly, this outfit isn't just this!
このあともですね、びびっ！と驚くような、いろんなことが起こるかもしれない。
After this too, maybe all kinds of surprising things might happen.
この衣装もなんとこれだけではない！この衣装の可能性は無・限・大！ということなのでね。
This outfit is also not just this! The potential this outfit holds is infinite! So yeah.
ぜひみんなもね、絶対に逃がさな…絶対チェックですよ！
Everyone be sure not to miss it... be sure to check it out!
はい、ほんとにね、このあとも…すばるもね、いまねドキドキするような、ね、びっくりすることがたくさん起こるので、ぜひチェックしてみてください、うん！
Yeah, really, after this, Subaru's heart is pounding, so many surprising things will happen, so please check it out, yep!
さあ、それではね、なんだ、もう次の曲の時間だ！
Now then, what, it's already time for the next song!
そろそろ行かねばならぬ。それではですね、次の曲に行きたいと思います！レッツ、ゴー！準備してくるよー！
It's about time to go. So then, I'd like to move on to the next song! Let's go! I'll go get ready!
この世で造花より綺麗な花はないわ
There are no flowers prettier than artificial ones in this world,
何故ならば全ては嘘で作られている antipathy world
because everything is made of lies, an antipathy world.
絶望の雨はあたすの傘を突いて
The rain of despair pierces my umbrella,
湿る前髪とこころの裏面 煩わしいわ
dampening my bangs and the back of my heart, so bothersome.
何時しか言の葉は疾み枯れきって
Before I knew it, my words withered away from sickness,
事の真があたすに熟れている
and the truth of things is ripening within me.
鏡に映り嘘を描いて
Reflected in the mirror, painting lies,
自我を見失った絵画
a painting that lost its ego.
何故何故何処かで踊っているのでしょう
Why, oh why, am I dancing somewhere?
簡単なことも解らないわ あたすって何だっけ
I don't even understand simple things—what was I again?
それすら夜の手に絆されて 愛のように消える
Caught in the hands of night, disappearing like love.
さようならも言えど咽び泣いた
Mute without even saying goodbye, I choked back tears.
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ 嘘に絡まれている あたすは antipathy world
Phony, phony, phony, wrapped in lies, I am an antipathy world.
パッパラパッパラパッパラパッパ
Pa-ppara-pappara-pappara-pappa,
謎々数えて遊びましょう
let's count riddles and play.
ッタッタラットットアララットッタ
Tatta-tarattotto-ararattatta,
何故何故此処が痛むのでしょう
why, oh why, does this place hurt?
散々ない日々は変わらないわ
These miserable days never change,
絶望の雨は止まないわ
and the rain of despair won't stop.
さようならも言えぬ咽び泣いた
Mute without even saying goodbye, I choked back tears.
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ 嘘に絡まれている あたすは antipathy world
Phony, phony, phony, wrapped in lies, I am an antipathy world.
何時しかそらの音がいやに鳴り合って
Before I knew it, the sounds of the sky clashed unpleasantly,
色の目があなたを融かしている
and colored eyes are melting you away.
鏡に映るあたすを欠いて
Chipping away the me reflected in the mirror,
誰しもが見間違った虚像
a virtual image everyone mistook.
何故して愛なんかものに群がり
Why do we flock to things like love,
それを欲して生きるのだ今日
and live desiring it today?
泳いでいる夜の電車が通り過ぎていく
Swimming through, the night train passes by.
踊り明かせよ
Dance until dawn!
パッパラパッパラパッパラパッパ
Pa-ppara-pappara-pappara-pappa,
謎々数えて遊びましょう
let's count riddles and play.
ッタッタラットットアララットッタ
Tatta-tarattotto-ararattatta,
何故何故此処が痛むのでしょう
why, oh why, does this place hurt?
散々ない日々は変わらないわ
These miserable days never change,
絶望の雨は止まないわ
and the rain of despair won't stop.
さようならも言えぬ咽び泣いた
Mute without even saying goodbye, I choked back tears.
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ 嘘に絡まれている あたすは antipathy world
Phony, phony, phony, wrapped in lies, I am an antipathy world.
何時しか空の願い嫌になりあって
Before I knew it, the sky's wishes grew sickeningly mutual,
色のメガネをどいて いる
removing colored glasses.
鏡に映るあたすを換えて
Replacing the me reflected in the mirror,
誰しもが見間違うたふりをして
pretending everyone mistook it.
愛なんてものに群がり
Flocking to things like love,
それを欲して生きるのだ今日
living desiring it today.
泳いでいる夜の電車が通り過ぎていく
Swimming through, the night train passes by.
踊り明かせよ
Dance until dawn!
パッパラパッパラパッパラパッパ
Pa-ppara-pappara-pappara-pappa,
謎々数えて歌いましょう
let's count riddles and sing.
ッタッタラットットアララットッタ
Tatta-tarattotto-ararattatta,
何故何処が傷むのでしょう
why, where does it hurt?
散々な日々は変わらないわ
These miserable days never change,
絶望の雨は止まないわ
and the rain of despair won't stop.
さようならまたねと呟いた
Muttering goodbye and see you later,
フォニイ フォニイ フォニイ 嘘に絡まれている あたすはフォニイ
phony, phony, phony, wrapped in lies, I am a phony.
antipathy world
いつしか空の願い嫌になりあって
Before I knew it, the sky's wishes grew sickeningly mutual,
異色のメガネをどいて いる
taking off unique glasses.
鏡に映るあたすを換えて
Replacing the me reflected in the mirror,
誰しもが見間違うたふりをして
pretending everyone mistook it.
愛なんてものに群がり
Flocking to things like love,
それを欲して生きるのだ今日
living desiring it today.
泳いでいる夜の電車が通り過ぎていく
Swimming through, the night train passes by.
踊り明かせよ
Dance until dawn!
パッパラパッパラパッパラパッパ
Pa-ppara-pappara-pappara-pappa,
謎々魂で歌いましょう
let's sing with riddle souls.
ッタッタラットットアララットッタ
Tatta-tarattotto-ararattatta,
何故何故ここが傷むのでしょう
why, oh why, does this place hurt?
どうかだけが走っている 秘密のフォニイ
Running only somehow, a secret phony.
落ちていく砂時計ばかり見てるよ
Just watching the falling hourglass,
さかさまにすればほら また始まるよ
If you turn it upside down, it starts again.
刻んだだけ進む時間に
In the time that passes as it ticks,
いつか僕も入れるかな
Will I eventually be able to join in?
きみだけが過ぎ去った坂道の途中は
Only you, halfway up the hill you passed by,
あたたかな日だまりがいくつできてた
Warm sun puddles were forming.
ぼくひとりがここで優しい温もりを思い出している
I'm alone here, recalling the warmth and kindness.
きみだけを きみだけを 好きでいてよ
Only you, only you, I loved you.
風で目が滲んで 遠くなるよ
My eyes blur in the wind, you become distant.
いつでも覚えている なにものも変わっても
I'll always remember, even if everything changes.
ひとつだけ ひとつだけ ありふれたものだけど
Just one, just one, it's something ordinary,
見せてやる 輝きに満ちたそのひとつだけ
But I'll show you that one, filled with radiance.
きみだけを
Only you,
きみだけを 好きでいたよ
Only you, I loved you.
風で目が滲んで
My eyes blur in the wind,
遠くなるよ
You become distant.
二重で
Doubling over,
遠く
Into the distance,
なるよ
Fading away.
だれも憶えてる
Everyone remembers,
なにもかも変わっても
Even if everything changes,
ひとつだけ ひとつだけ
Just one, just one,
いつまでも 守っていく
I will protect it forever.
肌寒い日が続く もう春なのに
Though it's already spring, chilly days continue,
目覚まし時計より早く起きた朝
Mornings where you wake up earlier than the alarm clock.
三人分の朝ご飯を作るきみがそこに立っている
You, making breakfast for three, standing there.
きみだけが きみだけが そばにいないよ
Only you, only you, are not by my side.
昨日まですぐそばで僕を見てたよ
You were right next to me until yesterday.
きみだけが
Only you,
そばに
By my side,
いないよ
You're not here.
昨日まで
Until yesterday,
すぐそばで
Right by my side,
僕を見てたよ
You were looking at me.
きみだけを
Only you,
好きで
Loved you,
いたよ
I did.
きみだけと きみだけと 歌う唄だよ
With you, with you, it's a song I sing.
僕たちの ぼくたちの 刻んだ時だよ
It's our, our time that passed.
片方だけ続くなんて僕は嫌だよ
I don't want only one side to continue.
いつでも覚えている この町が変わっても
I'll always remember, even if this town changes.
どれだけの悲しみと出会うことになっても
No matter how much sadness we encounter,
見せてやる 本当は強かったときのことを
I'll show you the time when we were truly strong.
いつでも覚えている なにものも変わっても
I'll always remember, even if everything changes.
見せてやる 輝きに満ちたそのひとつだけ
I'll show you that one, filled with radiance.
いくよ！
Let's go!
今日もこの胸は張り詰めたまま
Today too I feel the tension in my chest,
今日もこの胸は 張り詰めたまま
Today too, my heart feels so strained,
放課後に包まれて 君を見ってる
as I look at you in the after-school glow.
lady,ready?
Lady, ready?
ずっと足並みは 揃わないまま
Our walking pace never matches up,
続くから ナイショだよ
so it's a secret,
少しずつね
step by step,
lady,ready?
lady, ready?
知りすぎて知らないから
I know too much, yet know nothing at all—
聞こえないふりが上手になって
and I've gotten so good at pretending not to hear.
ねえ 深呼吸一つしたら目を開けて
Hey, after taking a deep breath, I open my eyes,
自問自答やめて何気なく おはようって言っちゃってる
stop overthinking, and casually say, "Good morning!"
飽きるくらい全部 君が欲しいよ ハートは涙でいっぱい
I want you so much I could get tired of it... My heart is full of tears.
恋のいろはとか まだわかってないんだ
I still don't know the basics of love.
何度も繰り返すけど 寸前でまた次回へ
It keeps repeating, and just when we're close, we move on...
sweetな乙女心は あいまい取り扱ってないのです
A sweet maiden's heart isn't that easily handled!
ねえ、これが I love you?
Hey, is this "I love you"?
やっと手に入れたはずのパノラマ
The panorama I finally got my hands on—
2歩進み 2歩下がる なんで？
two steps forward, two steps back... why?
だけど lady,ready?
But, lady, ready?
ゴールできなくちゃ止まれないから
I can't stop until I reach the goal,
わからないままでもいいよ だから
so it's fine not knowing, therefore—
lady,ready?
Lady, ready?
昨日の答えなんてさ 今日の答えの前では ほらね
Yesterday's answer is nothing before today's answer—see?
もう隠そうもないくらい好きだから
I love you so much I can't hide it anymore,
知らない事はいつか知れたらいいなって 言っちゃおうかな
so let's just say it's fine to learn what I don't know someday!
とりりとめないシーンでも 大事だからね アンダーラインを引いて
Even in uneventful scenes, they're important, so underline them.
恋の試験科目に追加しておいてよ
Add them to the curriculum of love tests!
時には君の心に 何百マイルのdistance?
Sometimes, how many miles is the distance to your heart?
なんてね気にしすぎかな だけどそれが本心なのです
I might be worrying too much, but those are my true feelings.
こんなあんないときはどうしたらいいの？ 慣れたメロディを口ずさむように
What should I do at times like this? Humming a familiar melody,
君の中の私はどこにいるの？ ぐるぐる回って四六時中、リサイタル！
where am I inside your heart? Spinning round and round all day and night—a recital!
いつかその日が来たら 大切な声を聞いて
Once that fateful day comes, listen to my precious voice—
恋に予約録画はありえないから逃がさないで
you can't record love in advance, so don't miss your chance!
飽きるくらい全部 君が好きだよ ハートは笑顔でいっぱい
I love you so much I could get tired of it... My heart is full of smiles!
恋のいろはをもっとわかりたいんだ
I want to learn just a bit more about the basics of love.
何度も繰り返すけど 寸前でまた次回へ
It keeps repeating, and just when we're close, we move on...
sweetな乙女心は 未だ取り扱ってないのです
A sweet maiden's heart still hasn't been dealt with!
ねえ、これが I love you?
Hey, is this "I love you"?
STAMP! STAMP! STAMP! IN ORBIT STAMP!
Someday I really really send it, precious for you!
Someday I really really send it!
いつかその日が来たら 大切な声を聞いて
Once that fateful day comes, listen to my precious voice—
恋に予約録画はありえないから逃がさないで
you can't record love in advance, so don't miss your chance!
飽きるくらい全部 君が好きだよ ハートは笑顔でいっぱい
I love you so much I could get tired of it... My heart is full of smiles!
恋のいろはをもっとわかりたいんだ
I want to learn just a bit more about the basics of love.
何度も繰り返すけど 寸前でまた次回へ
It keeps repeating, and just when we're close, we move on...
sweetな乙女心は 依然取り扱ってないのです
A sweet maiden's heart still hasn't been dealt with!
ねえ、これが I love you?
Hey, is this "I love you"?
Someday, I really really send it,
precious for you!
と いうことで Q&Aリサイタル！ でした！
And that was "Q&A Recital!"!
ふーーっ… ちょっとね、本当にいっぱい頑張ったからちょっとマジで… ふーっ。
Whew... Seriously, I worked so hard for this, I'm really... whew.
はあ…
Haah...
あっつ！
Hot!
ちょっと水飲んでくるね
I'll go grab a drink of water real quick!
待ってて、わあー！
Wait for me, wah!
うみー！
Umi!
はい、というわけですね、みんなライブを楽しんできてくれているかなー！
Yes, so, I wonder if everyone is enjoying the live!
わあー！
Wah!
声がたくさん聞こえます、というわけですね
I can hear lots of voices, so...
どうですか、この全部パージしたですね、スバルの新衣装！
What do you think of this fully purged new outfit of Subaru's?
しぐれりーかあちゃんがね、作ってくれました！かあちゃんありがとう！
Shigure Ui-mama made it for me! Mama, thank you!
後ろもですね、すっごく可愛いんですね、これ！可愛い！お花がね可愛いです！
The back is super cute too! Cute! The flowers are so cute!
お団子みたいな帽子もね、ヒマワリも全部可愛いんですけれども、ありがとうございます！しぐれりーかあちゃんありがとね！
The bun-like hat and sunflowers are all so cute, thank you so much! Shigure Ui-mama, thanks!
はい、というわけで、それではですね、ここでグッズ告知タイムにいきたいと思います！
Yes, so now, let's move on to the merchandise announcement time!
まずはこっち！
First is this!
大空スバル活動4周年記念グッズイエーイ！
Oozora Subaru's 4th Anniversary Goods, yay!
それではフルセットの内容を見ていきましょう、どん！
Let's check out the contents of the full set, boom!
おおー！こちらですね、こちらがですね、フルセットの内容となっております！それでは、詳しくちょっとね、見ていこうかな！
Ooh! Here is the contents of the full set! Let's take a closer look!
まずはこちら、どん！おおー！ポップアップアクリルスタンド！
First is this, boom! Ooh! Pop-up acrylic stand!
というわけですね、これはしぐれりーかあちゃん描き下ろしのスバルの新衣装のですね、アクリルスタンドとなっております！
This is an acrylic stand featuring Subaru's new outfit, illustrated by Shigure Ui-mama!
ちょっとね、プラスチック好きだから作っちゃった（笑）はい、でこれ立体なのでぜひね、お部屋にね飾ってください！お願いします！わあー！
I love plastic so I went ahead and made it (laughs). Yes, and since it's 3D, please display it in your room! Please! Wah!
それでは続いてこちら、どん！えー、アクリルバッジです！
Next is this, boom! Um, acrylic badge!
これはですね、ぜひとも学校に職場に、そしてライブにですね、一緒にね、カバンにつけて連れて行ってください！
Please take this along with you to school, work, and live shows attached to your bag!
かがみ先生のね、描き下ろしとなっております。このスバル、あ、間違えた。このスバルすごくね、なんかなんか可愛いんです。お揃いの帽子をかぶっています。
Illustrated by Kagami-sensei. This Subaru, ah my bad. This Subaru is super cute. She's wearing a matching hat.
サムネイルのね、スバルもね、いるのでね、ぜひ記念にチェックしてみてください！
Check out the thumbnail Subaru too!
ショルダーバッグ！
Shoulder bag!
これはですね、あの、ショルダーバッグはペンライトですね、ペンライトがですね、お、入るぐらいのですね、大きさと入っているらしい。
This shoulder bag is said to be big enough to fit penlights!
なのでね、ぜひね、ライブなどにね、ライブなどに行くときにね、ぜひね連れて行ってください！これもおねがいします！
So please bring it with you when you go to live shows! Please take care of this too!
そしてですね、全部フルセットの特典はこちら、どん！ちょっとお手紙をね、書きました。
And the bonus for the full set is this, boom! I wrote a little letter.
ちょっと恥ずかしいんですけど、まあね、ぜひね、ぜひね、チェックしてみてください！ちょっとね、あんまりね、普段書かないんですけど、書いてみました！よかったらぜひフルセットを買って、スバルからのお手紙読んでください！
It's a bit embarrassing, but please check it out! I don't usually write much, but I wrote one! If you'd like, please buy the full set and read the letter from Subaru!
ということで、これがですね、グッズの告知になりました！わあ！
And that wraps up the merchandise announcement! Yay!
はい！そしてですね、なんとこのあと、まだライブは続くよな！続きます！
Yes! And what's more, the live continues after this! It continues!
もう終盤なんですけれども、え、もう終盤なのか、あっという間ですね！でもまだまだライブは続くので！
We're already near the end, huh? It went by so fast! But the live is still continuing!
それでは次はね、なんと！新曲があるとか、ないとか！ちょっとね、はい、ということで！
Next up, surprisingly! There might or might not be a new song! Well, anyway!
それではですね、せっかくなので、センターステージへワープしたいと思います！それでは行くぞ！せーの、ワープ！
So since we're at it, let's warp to the center stage! Here we go! Ready, set, warp!
はい！ということで、早速行きたいと思います！それでは新曲です、聞いてください、「スターライト」！
Yes! So let's get right into it! Here is the new song, please listen: "Starlight"!
描いた未知のキャンバス 重ねる景色
Painting an unknown canvas, layering the scenery,
繋いできて 繰り返していく衝動
Connecting and repeating impulses,
揺らいだ目の前に広がる世界
A world spreading out before my wavering eyes,
星屑のメロディ 歌に乗せた
Putting a stardust melody into song.
クラッと鮮やかに眩ませるように
Dazzlingly, brilliantly, to make you spin,
駆け抜けるよ スターライト
Running through, starlight!
描いた未知のキャンバス 重ねる景色
Painting an unknown canvas, overlapping scenery,
繋いでみて 繰り返していく衝動
Connecting and repeating impulses.
揺らいだ目の前に広がった世界
The wavering world spreading out before my eyes,
星屑のメロディ 歌に乗せた
Set to a stardust melody.
クラっと鮮やかに眩ませるように 駆け抜けてよ スターライト
Dazzlingly bright, running through, starlight!
we can fly そう僕らは
We can fly, yes, we
いつしか夢の中 引かれて
Were drawn into a dream before we knew it.
ただがむしゃらに走り続けたよ 無限の宇宙に響いた
Running recklessly on and on, echoing in the infinite universe.
キミを照らす声は
The voice illuminating you
どこへだってきらり 飛んでいけるんだ
Can fly shimmering anywhere at all!
愉快な仲間と歩いた非日常
The extraordinary days walked with cheerful friends,
掴んでみて 指先の一等星
Catching the first-magnitude star at my fingertips.
滲んでゆく目の前に広がった限界は
The blurred limits spreading out before my eyes,
皆の手重ねてぶっ壊して
We smashed through by joining all our hands.
吸い込まれそうな夜空を見上げて
Looking up at the night sky that seems ready to swallow us up,
今叫ぶよ スターライト
Now I'll shout it out, starlight!
i wanna be そう僕らは いつでも側で笑い合って
I wanna be, yes, we always laugh together by each other's side.
あふれる声が遠くこだまする
The overflowing voices echo far away.
願いのかけらを灯した キミの腕を引いて
Taking your hand that lit up fragments of wishes,
どこへだってきらり 飛んでいけるんだ
You can fly shimmering anywhere at all!
ちょこっと不安な日も 魔法をかけてハッピー
Even on slightly uneasy days, cast a spell for happiness.
百人力で乗り越えていこう
Let's overcome it with all our might!
アクアブルーに染まる 大空にめがけた
Aimed at the vast sky dyed in aqua blue,
鼓動が弾んでく
Our heartbeats start to bound.
we can fly そう僕らは この日をずっと待ってたんだ
We can fly, yes, we've been waiting for this day all along.
まだ覚めないで
Don't wake up yet.
starlight 僕らは止まらない その光が消える1秒前まで走り続けるよ
Starlight, we won't stop, keeping on running until a second before that light fades.
無限の宇宙に響いた キミを照らす声を
Echoing in the infinite universe, the voice illuminating you,
強く抱いて きらり 輝いてゆけ
Hold it tight, shimmering, and shine on!
次で最後の曲になります！
This will be the final song!
この4年間スバルはみんなとここまで歩いて来れてとっても幸せでした！
I've been so happy walking this far with everyone over these 4 years!
これからもどんどん歩いていこうと思うので応援よろしくお願いします！
I plan to keep walking on, so I'd appreciate your continued support!
それでは聞いてください、最後の曲は「アカシア」！
Now, please listen, the final song is "Acacia"!
透明よりも綺麗なあの輝きを確かめにいこう
Let's go confirm that brilliance, even clearer than transparency.
そうやって始まったんだよ
That's how it all began, you know.
たまに忘れるほど強い理由 冷たい雨に濡れるときは
A reason strong enough to almost forget at times. When getting soaked in cold rain,
足音比べ 騒ぎながらいこう
Let's go making a racket comparing our footsteps.
太陽の代わりに歌を 君と僕と世界の声で
Singing in place of the sun, with the voices of you, me, and the world.
いつか君を見つけたときに 君に僕も見つけてもらったんだな
When I found you someday, you must have found me too.
今目が合えば笑うだけさ 言葉の外側で
Now, if our eyes meet, we just smile outside of words.
ゴールはきっとまだまだだけど もう死ぬまでいたい場所にいる
The goal is surely still far off, but we're in a place we want to stay until we die.
隣で 君の側で 魂がここだよって叫ぶ
Right next to you, by your side, my soul cries out that this is it.
泣いたり笑ったりする時 君の体が揺れる時
When crying or laughing, when your life trembles,
誰より 近くで 特等席で 僕も同じように息をしていたい
Closer than anyone, in the best seat, I want to breathe just the same way.
君の一歩は僕より遠い 間違いなく君のすごいところ
Your stride is farther than mine, undeniably your amazing feat.
足跡は僕の方が多い 間違いなく僕のすごいところ
My footprints are more than yours, undeniably my amazing feat.
真っ暗闇が怖いときは 恐さを比べ ふざけながらいこう
When pitch-black darkness is frightening, let's compare our fears and joke around as we go.
透明より綺麗な その輝きを確かめにいこう
Let's go verify that brilliance more beautiful than clarity,
そうやって始まったんだよ たまに忘れるほど強い理由
that's how it all began, a reason strong enough to almost forget.
冷たい雨に濡れる時は 足音比べ 騒ぎながらいこう
When soaked in cold rain, let's make noise comparing our footsteps.
太陽の代わりに唄を 君と僕と世界の声で
Singing a song instead of the sun, with the voices of you, me, and the world.
いつか君を見つけた時に 君に僕も見つけてもらえたんだな
When I found you someday, you must have found me too.
今目があえば笑うだけさ 言葉の外側で
Now when our eyes meet, we just smile beyond words.
ゴールはきっとまだまだだけど もう死ぬまでいたい場所にいる
The goal is surely still far off, but I'm already where I want to be until I die.
隣で (隣で) 魂がここだよって叫ぶ
Right beside you (right beside you), my soul cries out that it's right here.
泣いたり笑ったりする時 君の命が揺れる時
When you cry or laugh, when your life trembles,
誰より (近くで) 特等席で 僕も同じように息をしていたい
more than anyone (close by), from the front row, I want to be breathing just like you.
君の一歩は僕より遠い 間違いなく君の凄いところ
Your step is further than mine, undoubtedly your amazing part.
足跡は僕の方が多い 間違いなく僕の凄いところ
My footprints are more numerous, undoubtedly my amazing part.
真っ暗闇が怖い時は 恐さを比べ ふざけながらいこう
When pitch darkness is scary, let's compare our fears and joke around.
太陽がなくても歩ける 君と照らす世界が見える
We can walk without the sun, we can see the world you and I illuminate.
言えない事 聞けないまままで 消えない傷の意味知らないままで
Without being able to say or ask, without knowing the meaning of the unfading scars,
でも 目が合えば笑えるのさ 涙を挟んでも
but when our eyes meet we can smile, even with tears in between.
転んだら手を借りてもらうよりも 優しい言葉選んでもらうよりも
Rather than having you lend a hand when I fall, rather than having you choose gentle words,
隣で (隣で) 信じてほしいんだよ どこまでも一緒に行けると
right beside me (right beside me), I want you to believe we can go anywhere together.
ついに辿り着くその時 夢の正体に触れる時
When we finally arrive, when we touch the true form of our dreams,
必ず (近くで) 一番側で 君の目に映る景色にいたい
definitely (close by), right by your side, I want to be in the scenery reflected in your eyes.
あの輝きを 君に会えたから見えたあの輝きを
That brilliance—the brilliance I could see because I met you—
確かめにいこう どんな最後が待っていようとも もう離さない手を繋いだよ
let's go verify it, no matter what ending awaits, we've joined hands, never to let go.
隣で (隣で) 君の側で 魂がここだよと叫ぶ
Right beside you (right beside you), by your side, my soul cries out that it's right here.
そして理由が光る時 僕らを理由が抱きしめる時
And when the reason shines, when the reason embraces us,
誰より (近くで) 特等席で 僕の見た君を 君に伝えたい
more than anyone (close by), from the front row, I want to tell you about the you I saw.
君がいる事を 君に伝えたい
I want to tell you that you are here.
そうやって始まったんだよ
That's how it all began.
オーイェーイェーイェーイェー
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah...
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!